DANIEL ROBINSON

20 Silvermere Close, Ramsbottom, BL0 9WH

Mobile: 07435 427248 E-mail: dan.robinson@aalotto.com

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a highly motivated and passionate manager specialising in Cloud and Virtual Environments, following an ITIL methodology. Prior to my leadership roles I have gained over 15 years experience providing IT support in various industries including financial, energy and private sectors. Having been exposed to a wide range of different technologies, both as an engineer and a manager, I am enthusiastic about utilising my current skill set whilst also learning new technologies and embracing new challenges. I adapt well to change and set myself and my staff high challenging targets.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

GCI Cloud & UC Manager Aug 2017 – Present

- Leading a technical team of 11 staff in the Cloud and UC 2nd line support area providing support for multiple customers across various platforms
- Responsible for all recruiting within the Cloud and UC team
- Conducting 121s, appraisals and personal development plans, ensuring all staff have realistic and measurable targets and objectives
- Provide detailed platform availability reports
- Monitor and report on all SLAs and KPIs, ensuring individual and team targets are met and exceeded
- Responsible and accountable for 95% patch compliance for both critical and security updates and Cumulative Updates for all customers VMs
- Take ownership of operational handovers from other teams patching, certificate renewals, monitoring
- Ensure all work is logged in ITSM tool in the form of time entries and billable time targets are met
- ITSM queue management responsible for maintain and exceeding SLA targets on incidents and requests and ensuring the standard operating procedures are adhered to
- First point of escalation for all customers
- Individual and team targets for identifying risk and converting to revenue
- Monetise support accountable for identifying out of scope work and creating chargeable change
- Ensure all processes are followed and all changes adhere to change control policies
- Continual service improvements identify and carry out cost saving exercises and document new processes

GCI (Formerly Outsourcery) Senior IT Operations Executive Sept 2016 - Aug 2017

- Provide technical 2nd line support to all customers with emphasis on Microsoft Exchange, Microsoft Lync
 & Skype for Business and Microsoft Dynamics CRM on Multi-Tenant platforms and dedicated VMs
- Troubleshoot issues on Domain Controllers, SQL and Application servers
- Designing, implementing, testing and supporting Lync and Skype for Business solutions
- Provision and support direct and indirect Microsoft O365 tenants as a 2 Tier Cloud Service Provider (CSP)
- Patching customers VMs using SCCM in accordance with Change Control
- Maintain and update DNS settings for hosted domains and domain and SSL registrations
- Test new rollouts and updates on multiple systems in test environments prior to release
- Adhere to the Change Control system, seeking authorisation for any changes that may impact systems
 availability, security or capacity in advance of the change. Where changes are made for service
 restoration, complete retrospective changes to ensure accurate records are kept for all services, following
 an ITIL methodology
- Manage and coordinate P1 and Major Incidents with predefined SLAs
- Work in a busy environment ensuring all SLAs and KPIs are met and consistently exceeded
- Management responsibilities, including but not limited to, interviewing new candidates, conducting technical examinations, preparing training schedules and mentoring new employees
- Work to and aid in the development of the technical standards, processes and working practices of the team
- Protect all information relating to the client, partner or internal customers at all times ensuring the application of DPA where required and adhere to all elements of the Company's ISO standards and business policies

Other roles held include:

Technical Support Executive for Outsourcery, Manchester
 Remote Support Analyst for Capita Managed IT Solutions, Belfast
 Desktop Support Analyst for Wood Group, Texas, USA
 Desktop Support Analyst for Willbros Construction, Texas, USA
 Energy Trader Support Analyst for BP Energy, Texas, USA
 Desktop Support Analyst for Northern Rock Group Plc, Newcastle
 Feb 2014 - Sept 2014
 Dec 2011 - Feb 2014
 Feb 2009 - July 2011
 Oct 2008 - Dec 2008
 Jan 2006 - Oct 2008
 Feb 2001 - Sept 2005

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Multi-Tenant Cloud systems
- Public and Private Cloud Systems
- Microsoft Office 365 and Azure
- All versions of Microsoft Windows
- Microsoft Server 2003, 2008 / 2012
- PowerShell V3.0
- SCCM Software Deployment and Patching
- SCOM Monitoring and Alerting
- SolarWinds Monitoring
- Active Directory & Group Policy
- Parallels provisioning & billing
- Microsoft Dynamics CRM 2011, 2013, 2015
- Microsoft Lync & Skype for Business Server
- Microsoft Office versions 97 2016
- Altiris Deployment and Notification Server
- IVR Systems Clarity / Enghouse

- Cisco IP Phone & Unified Call Manager
- Polycom device and configuration
- Blackberry, BES, iPhone and Smartphone
- FortiClient, Cisco & Checkpoint VPN software
- Symantec Ghost Disk Imaging Software
- Terminal Services, PC Anywhere, VNC & VMM
- AutoCAD Licensing, Installation and setup
- CRM, Infra, RMS, Altiris & Remedy Fault logging software
- Energy Share Trading Applications
- Microsoft Exchange Admin 5.5
- Novell Netware 5 & 6.5
- Novell Client (all versions) including ZEN
- CTS (Branch front counter systems)
- ATM hardware, software break fix & ATM IP network knowledge
- Calyx Data Control & PGP Encryption software

KEY ACHIEVEMENTS

•	Successful acceptance and management of operational activities	Nov 2018
•	Full reorganisation of all customer facing documentation on the external portal	May 2016
•	Sole technical back-end resource for Windows 7 upgrade project for 3000+ users	Dec 2013
•	Involvement in major global domain migration projects	Jan 2011
•	Data Centre network migration project	Oct 2005
•	Finalised all Operational acceptance documentation for Anti-Money laundering project	Jun 2004
•	Heavy involvement in a major migration of the WAN, LAN and ATM network	Sep 2001

EDUCATION & TRAINING HISTORY

 Core Solutions of Microsoft Sky 	pe for Business 2015	Apr 2017
 Applications and Customisation 	in Microsoft Dynamics CRM 2015	Jun 2016
 DOSD Certified (Dell Online Se 	If Dispatch)	Nov 2010
 Energy trading applications: Ep 	silon, Nucleus, FOS, Entegrate, Cactis, ET	Jul 2006
 Netware 6 and Console one ad 	ministration	Dec 2003
 Windows XP Professional Insta 	llation and Administration	Sept 2003
 How to maintain, upgrade and t 	roubleshoot PCs	Feb 2002
ITIL Foundation		Sep 2001
 HNC Computing for Business, I 	Jniversity of Northumbria	Jul 2000
 HNC Business Information Tecl 	nnology. University of Northumbria	Jul 1998

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Linkedln: https://uk.linkedin.com/in/daniel-robinson-84637a15

Hobbies: Hiking, Cooking, Real and Craft Ale enthusiast

Driving Licence: Full UK licence held References: Available on request